Office of Analytical Studies fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Office of Analytical Studies fonds
1965 - 2001
F-52
2.5 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Institutional Research and Planning
Institutional Research and Planning compiles, analyzes, and reports on information regarding Simon Fraser University, such as enrollment and attrition, faculty salaries, course grades, instructional activities, facilities, and other matters. The office also analyzes phenomena of interest to university administration, faculty, and students, such as employment demand and various economic circumstances. The office also produces a yearly Fact Book, containing information on various aspects of SFU activities.
Until 1974, statistics and other data were collected by the Academic Planner, the Bursar, and the Registrar. In that year the position of Academic Planner was eliminated and the incumbent, John Chase, was named the first Director of Institutional Studies. In 1975, the name of the office was changed from Institutional Studies to Analytical Studies. In 1981, the Director's position was renamed Executive Assistant to the President/Director (Analytical Studies). By 1984, the name of the position was changed back to Director of Analytical Studies, and the position was then filled by Dr. Walter Wattamaniuk. In 2007 the name of the office was changed to Institutional Research and Planning.
From 1974 to 1984, the office reported directly to the President. By 1986, the office began reporting to the Vice-President, Academic.
published
Full
Revised
The title of the fonds is based on the name of the creating body at the time of the latest records in the fonds.
Fonds consists of records arising from the activities of the Analytical Studies office. Fonds includes correspondence, memoranda, reports, meeting agendas and minutes, statistical studies, publications, and other materials.
All accessions have been processed as of June 2003.
Further accruals are expected.
Consult the inventory to the Academic Planning fonds (F 49) and the Vice-President, Finance and Administration (F 28). The latter contains the records of the Office of the Bursar.
The fonds includes records containing personal information. Access to these files is restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review some files may be restricted in accordance with the FOI/POP Act. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions, subseries descriptions, and file lists are available.
- Director's correspondence, 1968 - 1991; F-52-1; 25 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of the Director's correspondence with other university departments and some external (non-SFU) organizations. While most of the correspondence relates to the functions of the Office of Analytical Studies, some of the correspondence was created by John Chase in his earlier roles as Academic Planner and chair of the Senate Committee on Undergraduate Studies.
  Activities, events and topics documented include statistical data in response to requests from departments and administrators; course development; and allocation of university space.
  Records include correspondence, proposals, reports, and statistics on enrollment, grades, teaching loads. salaries, instructional activity, student/faculty ratios and other academic issues.
  Files 28 to 166 were arranged by the archivist following the file classification system of the creator
  Further accruals to the series are expected.
  Some records may contain personal information relating to students, faculty or staff. Access to these files is restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review some files may be restricted in accordance with the FOI/POP Act. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  A file list is available.
  - Chronological File, 1968 - 1971; F-52-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Day Files, 1974; F-52-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1975; F-52-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 52-1)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Day Files, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Office Day Files and Miscellaneous and reports, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Office Day Files and Misellaneous and reports, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Office Day Files and Misellaneous and reports, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-26 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Day Files, 1980; F-52-1-0-0-27 (Archival box - small 52-2)
  - Faculty of Arts, 1970 - 1978; F-52-1-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.
  - Archeology, 1991; F-52-1-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.2.
  - Geography, 1969 - 1978; F-52-1-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.4.
  - History, 1969 - 1974; F-52-1-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.5.
  - Law and Society Program, 1973 - 1974; F-52-1-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.7.
  - Philosophy, 1970 - 1971; F-52-1-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.9.
  - Political Science, 1969 - 1973; F-52-1-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.10.
  - Psychology, 1969 - 1972; F-52-1-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.11.
  - School of Business Administration and Economics, 1971 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.13.
  - Business Administration, 1980; F-52-1-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.1.14.
  - Faculty of Education, 1972 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.2.
  - Professional Development Program (PDP), 1971 - 1972; F-52-1-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.2.2.
  - Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies, 1980; F-52-1-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.
  - Dean of Interdisciplinary Studies, 1972 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.1.
  - Fine and Performing Arts proposal, vol. 1, 1972 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.2.
  - Fine and Performing Arts proposal, vol. 2, 1972 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
  - Communications, 1978; F-52-1-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.3.
  - Kinesiology, 1969 - 1970; F-52-1-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 52-11)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.6.
  - Master of Natural Resource Management, 1978; F-52-1-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.3.10.
  - Faculty of Science, 1970 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.4.
  - Biological Sciences, 1969 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.4.3.
  - Chemistry, 1970 - 1971; F-52-1-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.4.5.
  - Mathematics, 1970 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.4.10.
  - Physics, 1970 - 1973; F-52-1-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.4.12.
  - Continuing Studies, 1980 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.5.
  - Downtown Centre, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.5.1.
  - Graduate Studies, 1971 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.7.
  - Centre for the Study of Higher Education, 1980 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-55 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.8.
  - Educational Foundation Centre, 1971; F-52-1-0-0-56 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.9.
  - Reading and Study Centre, 1975 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 2.10.
  - Analytical Studies -- purpose/activities/ projects/research, 1974 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-58 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3..
  - Research and development support, 1980 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-59 (Archival box - standard 52-12)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.1.1.
  - Labour market, 1977 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-60 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.1.2.
  - Public opinion, 1980 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-61 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.1.3.
  - Institutional research organizations, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-62 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.1.4.
  - General, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-63 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.1.5.
  - Fact book, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-64 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.2.
  - Students, 1977 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-65 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.
  - Enrolment, analyses, attrition, forecasting, vol. 1, 1970 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-66 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.2.
  - Enrolment, analyses, attrition, forecasting, vol. 2, 1970 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-67 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
  - Student retention and attrition, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-68 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.2.1.
  - Student socioeconomic studies, 1979 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-69 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.3.
  - Student evaluations of faculty and courses, 1972 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-70 (Archival box - standard 52-13)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.4.
  - Student lapse time for degees, 1972; F-52-1-0-0-71 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.5.
  - F.T.E. student to F.T.E. faculty ratios, 1973 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-72 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.6.
  - Student citizenship, 1972 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-73 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.7.
  - Drop out students, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-74 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.8.
  - Graduate follow up, 1979 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-75 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.9.
  - Enrolment limitation, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-76 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.10.
  - Aptitude and achievement tests, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-77 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.10.1.
  - Age analysis, 1976 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-78 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.11.
  - Geographic profile, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-79 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.12.
  - [Sex of students], 1978; F-52-1-0-0-80 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.13.
  - Cost / student, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-81 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.14.
  - Communication skills, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-82 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.15.
  - Enrolment models, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-83 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.16.
  - University student profile, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-84 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.18.
  - Undergraduate student enrolment by program, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-85 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.19.
  - International students, 1978 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-86 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.20.
  - General (students), 1982; F-52-1-0-0-87 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.3.21.
  - Courses and programs, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-88 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.
  - New course materials format and correspondence, 1972; F-52-1-0-0-89 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.1.
  - New program proposal format and correspondence, 1976 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-90 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.2.
  - Numbering of courses, 1971; F-52-1-0-0-91 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.3.
  - Innovation centres, 1980; F-52-1-0-0-92 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.4.
  - Instructional activity analysis, 1976 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-93 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.5.
  - [Instructional activity analysis], 1981; F-52-1-0-0-94 (Archival box - standard 52-14)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.5.1.
  - Academic indices, 1980; F-52-1-0-0-95 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.6.
  - Low course enrolment analyses, 1977 - 1978; F-52-1-0-0-96 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.7.
  - Instructional quality, 1980 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-97 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.8.
  - Distribution of regular scheduled undergraduate courses by course size, 1979; F-52-1-0-0-98 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.9.
  - Course scheduling, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-99 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.10.
  - Couse drop date file, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-100 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.10.1.
  - Communication skills, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-101 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.11.
  - Comparative faculty costs, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-102 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.12.
  - Frequency of course offerings, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-103 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.13.
  - Study abroad, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-104 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.4.14.
  - Staff, 1972 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-105 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.
  - Instructional (non-faculty), 1981; F-52-1-0-0-106 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.1.
  - Academic / non-academic staff analyses (profiles), 1982; F-52-1-0-0-107 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.1.1.
  - Instructional staff definitions, 1974 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-108 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.1.2.
  - Faculty / APSA, 1978 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-109 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.
  - Utilization of faculty resources, 1971; F-52-1-0-0-110 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.1.
  - Faculty discrimation studies, 1972 - 1975; F-52-1-0-0-111 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.2.
  - Academic to non-academic staff analyses, 1977 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-112 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.3.
  - Faculty demographics, 1977 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-113 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.5.
  - [Sex of students, faculty], 1980 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-114 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.5.1.
  - Citizenship, 1974 - 1977; F-52-1-0-0-115 (Archival box - standard 52-15)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.5.2.
  - F.T.E. student / F.T.E. faculty ratios / tenure, 1978 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-116 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.4.
  - Faculty research and profile, 1978 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-117 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.6.
  - Faculty degrees, 1979; F-52-1-0-0-118 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.7.
  - Status of women, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-119 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.8.
  - Graduate supervision, 1977; F-52-1-0-0-120 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.9.
  - Faculty activity, 1969 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-121 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.2.10.
  - Support / AUCE, 1976 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-122 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.3.
  - Support staff analysis, 1976 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-123 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.3.1.
  - Salaries, 1978 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-124 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.4.
  - Faculty salaries / negotiations, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-125 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.4.1.
  - Executive compensation, 1976 - 1980; F-52-1-0-0-126 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.5.4.2.
  - Degree designations, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-127 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.6.
  - Departmental grading studies, 1972 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-128 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.6.1.
  - Grade inflation, 1979; F-52-1-0-0-129 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.6.2.
  - Facilities, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-130 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.7.
  - General (facilities), 1982; F-52-1-0-0-131 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.7.5.
  - Financial, 1974 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-132 (Archival box - standard 52-16)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.
  - Cost performance indicators, 1972 - 1977; F-52-1-0-0-133 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.1.
  - Economic impact study, 1980 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-134 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.3.
  - Economic returns to education in Canada, 1978; F-52-1-0-0-135 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.3.1.
  - Enrolment, 1975 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-136 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.6.1.
  - Provincial operating grant formula, 1975 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-137 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.8.6.2.
  - Inter-institutional [and] resource allocation, 1973 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-138 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.
  - Institutional research data elements, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-139 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.1.
  - SFU [and] Capilano College cost study, 1974 - 1975; F-52-1-0-0-140 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.2.
  - Provincial enrolment and resource allocation models, 1971 - 1981; F-52-1-0-0-141 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.3.
  - Inter-university enrolment models, 1970 - 1974; F-52-1-0-0-142 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.4.
  - Affiliated status of private colleges, 1978 - 1979; F-52-1-0-0-143 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.5.
  - Feedback to colleges [and] high schools, 1979 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-144 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.6.
  - University student questionnaire, 1981 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-145 (Archival box - standard 52-17)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.7.
  - Department research activities at BC universities, 1981; F-52-1-0-0-146 (Archival box - standard 52-18)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.8.
  - Alumni questionnaire, 1982; F-52-1-0-0-147 (Archival box - standard 52-18)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.9.
  - Provincial university comparisons and correspondence, 1976 - 1982; F-52-1-0-0-148 (Archival box - standard 52-18)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.9.10.
  - University day, 1972 - 1974; F-52-1-0-0-149 (Archival box - standard 52-18)
    Creator's original file classification code: 3.10.1.